A Guide to the Fielding Dawson Papers 1978.0003
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
Fielding Dawson Papers
1926-1997
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
1978.0003
50.25 Linear Feet
Writings, correspondence, artwork, publications and photographs of short story writer, novelist, poet, artist, and teacher Fielding Dawson. Dawson was known for his "stream-of-consciousness" style of writing and for his vivid memoirs of his time spent as a student at Black Mountain College. The papers contain some drawings and memorabilia, including posters, flyers, brochures, and bulletins, from Black Mountain College.
Biography/History
Short story writer, novelist, poet, artist, and teacher [Guy] Fielding [Lewis] Dawson was born on August 2, 1930 in New York, NY. His mother, poet Cara Alban Byars Dawson, helped inspire his career as an author when, in giving him a typewriter for his fifteenth birthday, she dared him to become the next William Saroyan. Dawson's father, Clarence, was a journalist and died when he was twelve-years-old. Dawson spent his formative years in Kirkwood, Missouri, and enrolled at Black Mountain College (North Carolina) in 1949. He was drafted as a conscientious objector in 1953 and worked as a cook in a German military hospital.
While at Black Mountain, Dawson was instructed by poet Charles Olson and painter Franz Kline, both of whom became father figures for him. Although Dawson had already published two works, Kline's influence is apparent in Dawson's book An Emotional Memoir of Franz Kline (1967), written after the artist's death in 1962. Olson and Black Mountain had a significant influence on his writing; The Black Mountain Book (1970) documented life at the school from Dawson's perspective. Dawson was also part of the 1960s Beat movement in New York City, where he relocated and remained for life after his military service. In New York, he frequented artistic and literary hotspots including the Cedar Bar and Max's Kansas City (a restaurant and nightclub) where he interacted with artists like Kline, Jackson Pollock, Willem de Kooning, Robert Motherwell, and Philip Guston.
Although recognized in the beginning of his career for his illustrations and collages, Dawson soon focused on his writing. In a five-decade-long writing career, he published 23 books including stories, novels, memoir, and poetry. His stories have appeared in numerous literary magazines, including Blind Date, Bombay Gin, Conjunctions, Friction, House Organ, Pharos, River Styx, Shiny, Transfer, Witness, and The World.
Dawson's writing has been compared to that of Henry James. He was greatly influenced by James Joyce; like Joyce's Portrait of the Artist as a Young Man (1916), much of Dawson's works are auto- or semi-autobiographical "portraits" dealing with the artistic process. Some works—such as The Greatest Story Ever Told (1973)—also rely on the unconscious; they express the narrator's developing, ever-changing vision of the world. This reliance on the unconscious is indicative of Dawson's fascination with psychotherapist Carl Jung, whose theories influence his book Thread (1964), which sews together the early stages of Dawson's life as a child and as an artist. Dawson himself underwent psychotherapy for a number of years; the influence of these sessions is evident in the stories "The Sun Rises into the Sky," (1974) and "The Man Who Changed Overnight" (1976), among others.
Much of Dawson's literature has been published by Black Sparrow Press. Some of his more notable works include: Krazy Kat, The Unveiling, and Other Stories (1969), his first novel Open Road (1970), the Penny Lane trilogy (1977, 1981), Krazy Kat [and] 76 More: Collected Stories 1950-1976 (1982), and Virginia Dare: Stories, 1976-1981 (1985). Tiger Lilies: An American Childhood (1984) and 3 x 3 (written with Michael Rumaker and Paul C. Metcalf, 1989) are among his non-Black Sparrow publications.
Dawson was a creative writing teacher at Colorado's Naropa Institute and began hosting writing classes in prisons (Rikers Island, Attica, and Sing-Sing) beginning in 1984. He taught writing in US prisons for 17 years while also working with at-risk teenagers in alternative high schools. A passionate teacher and an advocate for prison reform, he later became the chairperson for the P.E.N. Prison Writing Committee. His last published piece, No Man's Land (2000), was colored by these experiences.
Dawson married psychologist Barbara Kraft in 1962; the two later divorced in 1976. Field Dawson died on January 5, 2002, leaving behind his wife, Susan Maldovan.
Sources:
Dawson, Fielding. "The Vertical Fields." Classic Short Stories. B and L Associates, Bangor, ME, 1995-2007. Web. 30 March 2012.
"Fielding Dawson." Contemporary Authors Online. Detroit: Gale, 2002. Literature Resource Center. Web. 2 Apr. 2012.
Hrebeniak, Michael. "Fielding Dawson: Writer at the heart of America's postwar avant-garde." Guardian News. The Guardian, 5 Apr. 2002. Web. 30 March 2012.
Hrebeniak, Michael. "In Memoriam Fielding Dawson, 1930-2002." Jacket 16. Jacket Magazine, March 2002. Web. 18 April 2012.
Levitt, Aimee. "Fielding Dawson: The Best St. Louis Writer You've Never Read." RiverFrontTimes.com. River Front Times, 18 Aug. 2010. Web. 30 March 2012.
Scope and Content
The Fielding Dawson Papers cover the years 1926-1997 and represent literary and artistic works from all points in the creative process. The bulk of the papers is comprised of manuscripts, notes, drafts, and galley proofs of stories, essays, poems, books, reviews, and screenplays. Works in the collection consist of Dawson's unpublished manuscripts and published pieces, such as Krazy Kat, Open Road, and The Black Mountain Book. The papers include a large series of correspondence that reflect his friendships and artistic affinities; correspondents include Robert F. Kennedy and Jacob Javits, as well as literary figures like Louis Zukofsky, Charles Olson, and Robert Creeley. Business correspondence with writers and editors about Dawson's work, and a long series of correspondence between Dawson and his mother that began while he was a student at Black Mountain College, also resides in the correspondence series. The papers encompass artwork, drawings, and photographs featuring Dawson, and a large scrapbook. Of particular note is the collection of memorabilia collected by Dawson throughout his life, including posters, flyers, brochures, and bulletins from Black Mountain College.
Arrangement
Arranged in the following series: Writings, Correspondence, Works by Others, Photographs and Artwork, and Associated Publications.
Restrictions on Access
The collection is minmally processed. Access to recent additions however are unprocessed and subject to archivist approval.
Acquisition Information
Acquired in several installments from Fielding Dawson between 1978 and 1997.
Manuscripts (document genre); Works of Art; Videocassettes; Audiocassettes; Administrative records; Financial Records; Minutes (administrative records); Diaries; Newsletters; Oral histories (document genres); Newspapers; Press releases; Audio visual materials; Posters; Poems; bylaws (administrative records); Typescripts; Photocopies; Notes; Monographs; Interviews; Photographs; Publications (documents); Notebooks; Correspondence; Fliers (printed matter); Illustrations (layout features).; Actions and defenses; Galley proofs; Dawson, Fielding, 1930-2002
- Series I. Writings
  Scope and Contents
  Series I, WRITINGS, is composed of Dawson's literary works. These works have been placed into the following nine divisions: stories, essays, poems, plays, book manuscripts, reviews and criticism, screenplay, published copies of works, and fragments and miscellaneous. Each division is arranged alphabetically. The majority of these papers are unpublished draft with a fair amount of annotation.
  - Stories
    - A Winter's Sunrise (Box 1)
    - The Accident (Box 1)
    - Accumulated Frankenstein (Box 1)
    - A.E. Coppard in Nantucket (Box 1)
    - Aion (Box 1)
    - Aio Triptych (Box 1)
    - Air Trails (Box 1)
    - Ajax (Box 1)
    - Albert E. Honey Funeral Is Held… (Box 1)
    - Alice (Box 1)
    - The American (Box 1)
    - The American Sentry (Box 1)
    - An Artist Takes a Bus Ride (Box 1)
    - And Rembrandt (Box 1)
    - And Then, The Life Goes (Box 1)
    - Angel Eyes (Box 1)
    - An Incident: Mind Preposition (Box 1)
    - An Indulgence (Box 1)
    - Another Man (Box 1)
    - The Appointment (Box 1)
    - Arrowhead (Box 1)
    - At the Farm (Box 1)
    - At Twilight (Box 1)
    - The Autobiography of Philip Guston (Box 1)
    - Baby (Box 1)
    - The B & O to Cleveland (Box 1)
    - The Big Story (Box 1)
    - The Black Mountain Book (Box 1)
    - Blood Star (Box 1)
    - The Blue Ribbon Civilian (Box 1)
    - Bonaparte's Retreat (Box 1)
    - Bookbeat (Box 1)
    - Boy Blue (Box 1)
    - The Bridge (Box 1)
    - The Brooklyn Story (Box 1)
    - The C Minor Symphony (Box 1)
    - Cabbage Patch (Box 1)
    - Captains America (Box 1)
    - The Cedar (Box 1)
    - Chatter Box (Box 1)
    - Childhood (Box 1)
    - Christmas (Box 1)
    - Christopher Robin in New York (Box 1)
    - City Grapevine (Box 1)
    - The City Was So Hot… (Box 1)
    - Classical Symphony (Box 1)
    - Cleo (Box 1)
    - Color of Sienna (Box 1)
    - Contact (Box 1)
    - Cont of Round Midnight (Box 1)
    - The Convertible (Box 1)
    - The Crystal Souls (Box 1)
    - The Dancing Man (Box 1)
    - The Dark Penrod (Box 1)
    - The Date (Box 1)
    - Dear Mary Lou (Box 1)
    - Dear Mother (Box 1)
    - Dear Papa (Box 1)
    - Dear Rudy (Box 1)
    - Delma Ciminello (Box 1)
    - Detroit (Box 1)
    - The Diary (Box 1)
    - Dick Zeppenfield (Box 1)
    - Different People (Box 1)
    - A Different War (Box 1)
    - The Dike in the Pet Shop (Box 1)
    - Discovery in New York (Box 1)
    - The Discovery of America (Box 1)
    - Dr. Generosity's Reading (Box 1)
    - Dorothy Lessing (Box 1)
    - Dorothy Reo (Box 1)
    - Double People (Box 1)
    - Dream (Box 1)
    - Dream II (Box 1)
    - A Dream (Box 1)
    - The Dream (Box 1)
    - The Dream (Box 1)
    - Dream People (Box 1)
    - The Dream/ Thunder Road (Box 1)
    - Dreaming Man (Box 1)
    - Early in the Morning (Box 1)
    - The Eight Wonder (Box 1)
    - The End of an Illusion (Box 1)
    - The Enemy Down Below (Box 1)
    - Entelechy (Box 1)
    - The Express to New York (Box 1)
    - The Fact in the Casket (Box 1)
    - Faux Pas (Box 1)
    - The Figure in the Sky (Box 1)
    - First Word (Box 1)
    - For Ann (Box 1)
    - For Barbara (Box 1)
    - For Mother (Box 1)
    - A Fortunate man (Box 1)
    - A Forward (Box 1)
    - Franz Kline (Box 1)
    - From a Roadhouse on 66 (Box 1)
    - The Front Page (Box 1)
    - Freezing People (Box 1)
    - Friday (Box 1)
    - The Frog (Box 1)
    - The Fundamentals (Box 1)
    - Funny Thing (Box 1)
    - Galileo (Box 1)
    - The Girl Next Door (Box 1)
    - The Girl on the Bicycle (Box 1)
    - The Girl on the Corner (Box 1)
    - The Girl with the Pale Cerulean Eyes (Box 1)
    - The Girl with the Silver Harelip (Box 1)
    - The God (Box 1)
    - God Lives (Box 1)
    - God Red (Box 1)
    - The Good (Box 1)
    - Grammercy Park (Box 1)
    - The Grapevine (Box 1)
    - The Great Day (Box 1)
    - Green Sunday (Box 1)
    - Gus's Story (Box 1)
    - He Began Through Fields (Box 1)
    - Helen T. (Box 1)
    - Hello Central, Give Me No Man's Land (Box 1)
    - Hello, Sid? (Box 1)
    - Hernando's Hideaway (Box 1)
    - Her River (Box 1)
    - Her Womanly Heart (Box 1)
    - Hey Taxi (Box 1)
    - High and High Spade (Box 1)
    - The High and the Mighty (Box 1)
    - Highwaisted (Box 1)
    - The Highwayman (Box 1)
    - A High Narrative (Box 1)
    - His Keys (Box 1)
    - His Troopship Steamed Across (Box 1)
    - Homage to the Beatles (Box 1)
    - Home (Box 1)
    - The Hook (Box 1)
    - How It All Came About (Box 1)
    - How Supremely (Box 1)
    - Icarus (Box 2)
    - The Idea (Box 2)
    - The Indian Tree (Box 2)
    - The Idiot (Box 2)
    - In Fields (Box 2)
    - Inner Bodies (Box 2)
    - In the Flat Iron Building (Box 2)
    - In the White House… (Box 2)
    - Intro to the Army Book (Box 2)
    - The Invisible Boy (Box 2)
    - The Invisible Glass (Box 2)
    - Iron Henry (Box 2)
    - Janet Insley (Box 2)
    - Josie (Box 2)
    - Judy (Box 2)
    - The Jupiter Tone (Box 2)
    - Kings Rat (Box 2)
    - Kings Think (Box 2)
    - The King and the Burning Boy (Box 2)
    - Krazy Kat (Box 2)
    - Labor Day (Box 2)
    - The Labyrinthine Ways (Box 2)
    - Laid to Rest (Box 2)
    - Larry (Box 2)
    - The Last Look (Box 2)
    - Lately, I Find (Box 2)
    - The Light (Box 2)
    - A Linguistic Affair (Box 2)
    - The Little Boy and Mrs. Tong (Box 2)
    - Little Magazines (Box 2)
    - Little Women/ Lost Horizon (Box 2)
    - The Lone Cowhand
    - Loose Leaves (Box 2)
    - The Lovely Girl (Box 2)
    - Magnetic North
    - Main Street (Box 2)
    - The Major Circle (Box 2)
    - The Making of a President (Box 2)
    - Manhatten Crackup (Box 2)
    - The Man in the Dark Blue Suit (Box 2)
    - Man Steps into Space (Box 2)
    - The Man Who Changed Overnight (Box 2)
    - Massachusetts Breakdown 2 (Box 2)
    - The Meaning (Box 2)
    - Memory (Box 2)
    - The Men (Box 2)
    - The Messiah (Box 2)
    - The Messiah (2) (Box 2)
    - Mexico (Box 2)
    - Miscrocosmos (Box 2)
    - Mine Alone (Box 2)
    - The Miracle (Box 2)
    - Mirror Road (Box 2)
    - Mrs. Watson (Box 2)
    - Moibus Strip (Box 2)
    - Monday (Box 2)
    - Monday at 9 (Box 2)
    - The Monday Before Thanksgiving (Box 2)
    - The Moonbeam Kid (Box 2)
    - The Morning News (Box 2)
    - Mother (Box 2)
    - Movietone (Box 2)
    - My Memory (Box 2)
    - My Old Buddy (Box 2)
    - Mystery in Marin (Box 2)
    - A Mystery, In the Caribbean (Box 2)
    - Nantucket Incident (Box 2)
    - Narrative 3rd Person (Box 2)
    - A National Vignette (Box 2)
    - The Nature of the Universe (Box 2)
    - New American Fiction (Box 2)
    - A New Book (Box 2)
    - The News (Box 2)
    - New Years Eve – New York Anywhere (Box 2)
    - New York Central (Box 2)
    - Nightmare (Box 2)
    - No Feet (Box 2)
    - Note on a Day (Box 2)
    - Notes on Ernie Attwood (Box 2)
    - A November Dream (Box 2)
    - November Dreams (Box 2)
    - Nuclear Truth (Box 2)
    - NYG Show (Box 2)
    - Old Lady (Box 2)
    - On Christmas Eve (Box 2)
    - Playback (Box 2)
    - One (Box 2)
    - Open Road (Box 2)
    - Oriental Silence (Box 2)
    - Out of the Past (Box 2)
    - Overture (Box 2)
    - The Party (Box 2)
    - The Photograph (Box 2)
    - Pieace of Thread (Box 2)
    - Pirate One (Box 2)
    - Plus Tax (Box 2)
    - Post Script (Box 2)
    - Preface to the Dream Book (Box 2)
    - Pride of the Yankees (Box 2)
    - The Private Eye (Box 2)
    - Provincetown (Box 2)
    - Queen of the Ant-Hill (Box 2)
    - Red Impact (Box 2)
    - Reflections of the Steel (Box 2)
    - The Ring, the Peeper,… (Box 2)
    - Roots and Branches (Box 2)
    - Ross MacDonald (Box 2)
    - Round About Midnight (Box 2)
    - The Running Man (Box 2)
    - Ruth (Box 2)
    - Salad (Box 2)
    - Sandra's Story (Box 2)
    - Sandy (Box 2)
    - Santa's Revenge (Box 2)
    - The Savage Imprint (Box 2)
    - The Saw (Box 2)
    - School Days (Box 2)
    - A Selection from an Accumulation (Box 2)
    - The Sentry (Box 2)
    - She (Box 2)
    - She Will Be Home for Supper (Box 2)
    - A Ship Going Out (Box 2)
    - Ship O' Fools (Box 2)
    - The Singing Man (Box 2)
    - The Singing Man and the Beautiful Boy
    - Sister (Box 2)
    - Sketches from Childhood (Box 2)
    - Sightly Forever (Box 2)
    - A Slow Roll Over Haystacks (Box 2)
    - Slyly (Box 2)
    - Soldier's Road (Box 2)
    - Some History (Box 2)
    - Some Real Magic (Box 2)
    - Sometime September (Box 2)
    - The Source (Box 2)
    - Space Gate (Box 2)
    - Sparks (Box 2)
    - The Split Second (Box 2)
    - The Spring of 1946 (Box 2)
    - Spring Sequence (Box 2)
    - Stefan (Box 2)
    - Step by Step (Box 2)
    - Stories, 1952 (Box 2)
    - Storm (Box 2)
    - The Story (Box 2)
    - Straight Lines (Box 2)
    - Style Is Important (Box 2)
    - A Subjective Relationship (Box 2)
    - The Sun Rises into the Sky (Box 2)
    - The Tapestry and the Web (Box 3)
    - Teacher's and Soda (Box 3)
    - Teacher's Notes (Box 3)
    - The Terrible Stink (Box 3)
    - There Is a Man I know (Box 3)
    - This Was American History (Box 3)
    - Thomas Crimmins (Box 3)
    - Thomasina and the Miniature Deer (Box 3)
    - Those English Mysteries (Box 3)
    - Thread (Box 3)
    - Thread 2 (Box 3)
    - Three Fields of Dreams (Box 3)
    - Three Women (Box 3)
    - Thunder Road (Box 3)
    - Time Candy (Box 3)
    - Timex (Box 3)
    - The Time Man (Box 3)
    - The Tin Angel (Box 3)
    - Tish (Box 3)
    - To Al and Carol Likewise; Differently (Box 3)
    - To Dave Jones (Box 3)
    - Too Early for a Martini (Box 3)
    - To Reiterate (Box 3)
    - Tough Girl (Box 3)
    - Towards Forty (Box 3)
    - A Tragic Story (Box 3)
    - The Traveler (Box 3)
    - The Triangle on the Jungle Wall (Box 3)
    - The Turn of the Screw (Box 3)
    - Two City-Hospital Tales (Box 3)
    - Two Ducks (Box 3)
    - Two Vignettes (Box 3)
    - Ultramarine (Box 3)
    - The Unborn (Box 3)
    - Union Square (Box 3)
    - Universal International (Box 3)
    - The Unveiling (Box 3)
    - Up and Down (Box 3)
    - Up in New England (Box 3)
    - Urbana Illinois (Box 3)
    - The Vertical Fields (Box 3)
    - Vietnam and the Dominican Republic (Box 3)
    - Intro to Vietnam Stories (Box 3)
    - Vietnam Story (Box 3)
    - Vignette (Box 3)
    - War (Box 3)
    - The Voyage (Box 3)
    - Warm Simplicity (Box 3)
    - We (Box 3)
    - Webster Chicago (Box 3)
    - The Wendigo (Box 3)
    - Western Union (Box 3)
    - Whistle Down the Wind (Box 3)
    - Whistle While You Work (Box 3)
    - The White City (Box 3)
    - The Winner (Box 3)
    - The Word (Box 3)
    - The World of Henry Orient (Box 3)
    - World People (Box 3)
    - The Writer (Box 3)
    - X-Mas Eve (Box 3)
    - X-Mas Eve Dreams (Box 3)
    - The Ying and Yang Radio Repairman (Box 3)
    - You Can't Kid Me This Time (Box 3)
  - Essays
    - A Memory of Charley Olson (Box 3)
    - A Note on Four Early Stories (Box 3)
    - An Essay on Fiction (Box 3)
    - An Old Hat Gets Turned Inside out (Box 3)
    - Essay (Box 3)
    - Gossip from the Vine (Box 3)
    - Literary Pollution (Box 3)
    - Notes from a Nova Scotia and Cape Breton Journal (Box 3)
    - Notes from the Garbage Dump (Box 3)
    - On Applying for Grants (Box 3)
    - On Art Precisely (Box 3)
    - On Composer Stefan Wolpe (Box 3)
    - On Creeley (Box 3)
    - On the Dangers of Writers Teaching (Box 3)
    - On Death (Box 3)
    - On DeKooning (Box 3)
    - On Illusion (Box 3)
    - On Impact (Box 3)
    - On Inspiration (Box 3)
    - On Lardner (Box 3)
    - On Prayer (Box 3)
    - On Self-Destruction and Suicide (Box 3)
    - On Self-Destruction and Suicide in the Arts (Box 3)
    - On Writing Jokes (Box 3)
    - On Writing Jokes 2: Tarzan and Jane… (Box 3)
    - Saint Augustine Speaks (Box 3)
    - Shortstop as the Figure of Kinesis (Box 3)
    - The Diplomat (Box 3)
    - The Future of Publishing
    - The Man in the Dark Blue Suit (Box 3)
    - The Man in the Dark Blue Suit and other essays (Box 3)
    - Thoughts (Box 3)
    - Thoughts and Memories (Box 3)
  - Poems
    - 9 AM (Box 3)
    - An Airplane Ride for Union Guys (Box 3)
    - Benton Pride (Box 3)
    - Black (Box 3)
    - Blues for Gill (Box 3)
    - Blue Star (Box 3)
    - The Dark Penrod (Box 3)
    - Dirty Town (Box 3)
    - Do You Remember (Box 3)
    - e Out (Box 3)
    - Epsilon from Phonecia (Box 3)
    - A Face in the City (Box 3)
    - The Field (Box 3)
    - From Day to Day (Box 3)
    - For Bill DeKooning (Box 3)
    - Green Sunday (Box 3)
    - I Am the Man (Box 2)
    - I Kiss Angels (Box 3)
    - I Remember the Ghost Town (Box 3)
    - I Said (Box 3)
    - I See You in Your Little Apartment (Box 3)
    - I Stand in the Yard (Box 3)
    - I Tell You (Box 3)
    - It Is Twenty-five Minutes to Five (Box 3)
    - Kings Think (Box 3)
    - Kisses & Kill… (Box 3)
    - The Land of Love (Box 3)
    - Leo's Tune (Box 3)
    - The Little Mad Boy (Box 3)
    - The Man in his Boat (Box 3)
    - Muscatel (Box 3)
    - Night City (Box 3)
    - The Office Girls (Box 3)
    - On the Corner of 14th Street… (Box 3)
    - The Plains Man (Box 3)
    - Poem (Box 3)
    - Poems, 1956-1967 (Box 3)
    - Puerto Rican Mother (Box 3)
    - Returning from Work, I Found You… (Box 3)
    - The River (Box 3)
    - Sad Poem to Franz Kline (Box 3)
    - Sentimental Poem (Box 3)
    - A Slander of Being Rotten (Box 3)
    - A Solitary Decoration (Box 3)
    - Song Beholding the Spectacle… (Box 3)
    - Song of the Animals (Box 3)
    - Ten Songs for Children in Starched Shirts (Box 3)
    - There Are Places I'll Remember (Box 3)
    - The Thin Man (Box 3)
    - Three Poems with Color (Box 3)
    - Three Unexpected Responsibilities (Box 3)
    - To Live (Box 3)
    - To the Dead in Vietnam (Box 3)
    - Water Babigs (Box 3)
    - When I Was Twelve (Box 3)
  - Plays
    - Zeno (Box 3)
    - Five Short Plays (Box 3)
    - Four Plays (Box 3)
  - Book Manuscripts
    - A Great Day for a Ballgame (7 folders) (Box 4)
    - The Black Mountain Book (8 folders) (Box 4)
    - The Greatest Story Ever Told (6 folders) (Box 4)
    - Thread (Box 5)
    - Franz Kline: An Emotional Memoir (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - Open Road (Box 5)
    - The Mandalay Dream (9 folders) (Box 5)
    - The Sun Rises into the Sky (Box 6)
    - Tiger Lilies (8 folders) (Box 6)
    - Oz with an X, A Pulp Fragment (Box 6)
    - Oz with an X, The Battle for New York (5 folders) (Box 6)
  - Reviews and Criticism
    - An Essay on Intuitive Fiction (Box 7)
    - Alice's Restaurant Cookbook (Box 7)
    - All the Short Poems of Louis Zukofsky (Box 7)
    - Art and Industry: A Conjecture (Box 7)
    - Art News Reviews (3 folders) (Box 7)
    - Art Reviews (2 folders) (Box 7)
    - The Autobiography of Malcom X (Box 7)
    - Backfire (Box 7)
    - James Baldwin (Box 7)
    - The Black Mountain Book and An Emotional Memoir of Franz Kline (Box 7)
    - The Blue Angel & The Third Man (Box 7)
    - Joel Brady (Box 7)
    - City Lights Journal 2 (Box 7)
    - Confessions from a Malaga Madhouse & … (Box 7)
    - The Construction of Bill Cushner (Box 7)
    - Continental Drift (Box 7)
    - Covering Ground (Box 7)
    - Death on the Nile & Murder in Retrospect (Box 7)
    - Decision at Delphi (Box 7)
    - The Drubbing of Nesterenko & First loves (Box 7)
    - EDIE An American Biography (Box 7)
    - Energy Made Visible & An Exploration in… (Box 7)
    - Entelechous Fiction (Box 7)
    - For Love (Box 7)
    - The George Washington Poems (Box 7)
    - Green Grapes & Modern Art (Box 7)
    - Gringos and Other Stories (Box 7)
    - Philip Guston (Box 7)
    - The Happy Hooker (Box 7)
    - Homage to Carl Jung (Box 7)
    - The Legend of Erje Ayden (Box 7)
    - Like Pharao's Eye, Like Onyx Stone (Box 7)
    - Little (Box 7)
    - Love Poems by Frank O'Hara (Box 7)
    - Memoirs of an Ex-Prom Queen (Box 7)
    - Movie Reviews (Box 7)
    - The Name (Box 7)
    - NOG (Box 7)
    - Olson's Human Universe (Box 7)
    - On Creeley's Third Change (Box 7)
    - On DeKooning (Box 7)
    - On Fear of the Word (Box 7)
    - On Franz Kline (Box 7)
    - On Ishmael Reed (Box 7)
    - On Journalism (Box 7)
    - On Karen Chaplin (Box 7)
    - On Larder (Box 7)
    - On Literary Pollution (Box 7)
    - On Mort Lucks (Box 7)
    - On Robert Creeley (Box 7)
    - On Seymour Krim (Box 7)
    - Pandora's Box (Box 7)